travis.manick@gmail.com (651) 278-6262 https://tmanick.github.io/



Travis holds more than 10 years of front- and back-end development experience. He loves pairing his development skills with a passion for user experience and accessibility to create and maintain high quality web projects. He has a curiosity and hunger to learn and utilize new technologies and practices.

SKILLS

- + Collaborate and communicate with clients and product managers to turn business needs into digital experiences.
- + Work solo or on small, focused teams to complete high quality, efficient goals.
- + Estimate time, cost, and capacity on web projects front-to-back.
- + Review and implement quality assurance testing, accessibility best practices, and SEO tools.
- + Develop and implement best practices and efficiency to improve product build time and reusability.
- + HTML5, CSS3, Javascript ES6 & jQuery | PHP, MySQL
- + Sketch, InVision, Photoshop, Adobe XD

PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

Target Accelerators

https://targetaccelerators.com/

- Worked with Target to create a new website to attract and inform new incubator candidates.
- The latest program saw application submissions increased by almost 400%.

Society of ProAdvisory

- A temporary microsite centered around Quickbook's ProAdvisor training program.
- Increased program engagement by 1,200%.

EXPERIENCE

PERISCOPE / QUAD GRAPHICS, Minneapolis, MN

Senior Developer February 2018 - Present

Representative Clients: Arctic Cat, Truvia, Target, JCPenny, Trolli, UnitedHealth Group, Minnesota Lottery, Google, Quickbooks

ROBERT HALF TECHNOLOGY | THE CREATIVE GROUP, Minneapolis, MN

Developer April 2015 - April 2016, July 2017 - February 2018

Representative Clients: Optum, FirstScribe, Brandography.

SPYDER TRAP, Minneapolis, MN

Senior Developer August 2010 - April 2015, April 2016 - July 2017

Representative Clients: Deloitte, Cargill, Children's Hospitals and Clinics of Minnesota, Crystal Farms.

EDUCATION

CENTURY COLLEGE, White Bear Lake, MN

Visual Communication Technologies: Interactive Media

Actively participate with program's Advisory Committee